# **AKASHAY ANAND**

#### Lovely Professional University, Punjab

akashayanand1@gmail.com/Akashay-Anand

**\** +91 --

Punjab, INDIA

% linktree - Akashay Anand

in /akashay-anand

### **PROJECTS**

# Planetary - Serverless application Self-Learning Project

H July 2023 - August 2023

- cloud base backend application which uses 'nasa.gov' API to fetch the latest space image and metadata. And periodically sends this data packet to my phone number as an SMS.
- Function is written in JavaScript which will be running on NodeJS.
   Axios is used for API interaction. for SMS Twilio library is integrated with it to send messages whenever the lambda function gets evoked. This project is built around Serverless Framework and has been deployed on AWS Lambda
- Impact: The API is constrained by a rate limit of 1000 requests per hour, whereas the aws lambda can uphold 1 million requests and 3.2 million compute seconds per month in the free tier.

# Airport management system Self-Learning Project

max April 2021 - May 2021

- Technologies Used: Android Studio, Java, XML.
- A simulated version of an app that helps customers with the basic requirements related to the airport.

#### Notepad

#### **Exploratory Project**

∰ Feb. 2023

- Technologies Used: Java, Swing,
- Notepad Application to write and store plain text for Windows system.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **DSA Training**

#### **Coding Spoon**

## June 2023 - July 2023

**♀** LPU

• Learned the systematic way of approaching problems;

## ReactJS Training

#### Hitbullseye

**♀** LPU

• Learned core concepts of React;

## **Business Development Intern**

#### **Digita World**

## Aug 2020 - Sep 2020

- Brainstorming ideas in group discussion for Business growth.
- Contacting education entities in the Bihar region and generating leads

## **EDUCATION**

# B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

#### **Lovely Professional University**

Aug 2021 - Present

CGPA: 8.04

### **SKILLS**

Language: Java Python JavaScript
PHP HTML YAML
Framework/Technologies: NodeJS
Express js ReactJS
Tools/Software: Git/GitHub AWS
Linux Docker WordPress
DBMS: MySQL Mongo DB

### **COURSEWORK**

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Object Oriented Programming
- Operating Systems
- Database Management Systems
- Advanced Web Development
- Entrepreneurship and Business Basics

# POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY

- NSS unit Leader- NSS is one of the well-recognized student organization which is an Indian government sector public service program conducted by the Ministry of Youth Affairs and Sports of the Government of India.
- Technical Event Coordinator -Coordinated in an 'All India Research Championship 2020' (airc'20) hackathon associated with Techkriti IIT, Kanpur
- Event Management Organised events like EDM, Esports, etc., and Handled 1000+ strength of students while assuring corrective measures.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Solved more than 300+ DSA problems across all platform
- Onboard 1 sponsorship while working with event management team.